<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>planningadmin &#8211; G News Today</title>
	<atom:link href="https://staff.ramdajs.com/author/planningadmin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:32:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>‘I didn’t want to criticise Vinicius’ with tweet: La Liga’s Tebas</title>
		<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/i-didnt-want-to-criticise-vinicius-with-tweet-la-ligas-tebas/</link>
					<comments>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/i-didnt-want-to-criticise-vinicius-with-tweet-la-ligas-tebas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staff.ramdajs.com/?p=55</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[La Liga chief Javier Tebas insisted Thursday he didn’t mean “to criticise” Vinicius Junior following a charged exchange on Twitter after the Real Madrid forward was racially abused during a march. The incident on Sunday, when the 22-year-old Brazilian star was subjected to racist taunting as Real Madrid lost to Valencia, kicked up a storm...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-style-default"><img decoding="async" width="1222" height="687" src="https://staff.ramdajs.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/lllll_02.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-56"/></figure>



<p>La Liga chief Javier Tebas insisted Thursday he didn’t mean “to criticise” Vinicius Junior following a charged exchange on Twitter after the Real Madrid forward was racially abused during a march.</p>



<p>The incident on Sunday, when the 22-year-old Brazilian star was subjected to racist taunting as Real Madrid lost to Valencia, kicked up a storm over whether Spain is doing enough to stamp out racism in football.</p>



<p>Later, Vinicius hit out at La Liga on Twitter saying it “belongs to racists” prompting Tebas to respond with several tweets that appeared critical of the player.</p>



<p>“I didn’t want to criticise Vinicius,” Tebas told reporters.</p>



<p>“My frustration was my mistake. I understand that Vinicius is frustrated because he doesn’t understand about the division of powers (for dealing with racism), but I’m also frustrated because I do know about it and there were no sanctions.”</p>



<p>Tebas said he hadn’t yet spoken to Vinicius but would be willing to do so and would say, “‘I’m sorry if you felt offended but I wasn’t trying to attack you’ and I would tell him again that like him, I’m also frustrated.”</p>



<p>In his tweet on Sunday night, Tebas wrote, “before criticising and insulting La Liga, you need to be properly informed” about the division of powers when it comes to imposing sanctions.</p>



<p>Under Spanish law, La Liga can only identify and report cases of racism but it is not empowered to impose sanctions.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, it called for more sanctioning power to act against fans for violent, racist or xenophobic behaviour, saying it felt “powerless” when its incident reports failed to result in any punitive action.</p>



<p>‘A great player’<br>Tebas said only the Spanish football federation had the ability to impose sanctions and reiterated calls for La Liga to be granted sanctioning power.</p>



<p>“We want the power to act because with that, we’re sure that within months, we’ll be able to resolve this problem,” he said.</p>



<p>Tebas said that when he took over as league chief in 2013, the stadiums were filled with “racist and homophobic chanting. I remember people shouting ‘Messi is retarded’,” he said.</p>



<p>“We insisted that this disappear from the stadiums and we did it,” he said, adding, “We are very aware that Vinicius is being insulted because he’s such a great player.”</p>



<p>He also expressed frustration that no other body had supported La Liga when it filed legal complaints about racism in stadiums, especially when it came to the case of Vinicius.</p>



<p>“In all our complaints, we have filed suit alone, we’ve never been backed by any other institution and in Vinicius’ case, not even by Real Madrid,” he said after the club accused La Liga and the federation of being passive.</p>



<p>La Liga has filed various lawsuits in relation to racist abuse suffered by Vinicius</p>



<p>“Vinicius is different. He’s not your average player. I’m convinced that he’ll win the Ballon d’Or at some stage,” Tebas said, adding he hoped the Brazilian would keep playing in the Spanish league because “he’s a very important asset for his club and for La Liga”.</p>



<p>He said the league had been carefully watching Vinicius’ away games for any further signs of racial abuse.</p>



<p>Tebas said he was worried that what had happened could affect the Spanish league’s image, insisting that “Spain is not a racist country and Spanish football isn’t racist.”</p>



<p>“It’s a blow but there’s no point crying about it. We have to work to restore any reputation that may have been lost,” said Tebas, who said he doesn’t think the scandal will affect Spain, Portugal and Morocco’s joint bid for the 2030 World Cup.</p>



<p>“I hope this doesn’t affect it, we’re showing what we’re going and we will get better,” he said. “It’s still a long way off.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/i-didnt-want-to-criticise-vinicius-with-tweet-la-ligas-tebas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ken Loach at Cannes: &#8216;working class is undefeated&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/ken-loach-at-cannes-working-class-is-undefeated/</link>
					<comments>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/ken-loach-at-cannes-working-class-is-undefeated/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staff.ramdajs.com/?p=52</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At 86, British director Ken Loach showed he still had fighting spirit at Cannes, presenting his latest moving homage to working class solidarity and saying: &#8220;we&#8217;re still in the game&#8221;. Loach has had no fewer than 15 films in competition at the Cannes Film Festival &#8212; and won the top prize Palme d&#8217;Or twice. His...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1222" height="687" src="https://staff.ramdajs.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/eeeeeeee_02.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-53"/></figure>



<p>At 86, British director Ken Loach showed he still had fighting spirit at Cannes, presenting his latest moving homage to working class solidarity and saying: &#8220;we&#8217;re still in the game&#8221;.</p>



<p>Loach has had no fewer than 15 films in competition at the Cannes Film Festival &#8212; and won the top prize Palme d&#8217;Or twice.</p>



<p>His dedication to left-wing causes and showing the often harsh reality of working class Britain remains undimmed in his 16th entry, ‘The Old Oak’, which premiered on Friday.</p>



<p>It tells the story of a struggling pub in a depressed ex-mining town in northern England, whose landlord helps Syrian refugees despite his own problems.</p>



<p>Deadline called it a &#8220;vital, moving social parable&#8221; and The Guardian a &#8220;fierce final call for compassion&#8221;.</p>



<p>Despite widespread anti-immigrant feeling in Britain, Loach said there are still many working class communities who have shown solidarity with refugees.</p>



<p>&#8220;We have a tradition of solidarity born out of industrial struggle,&#8221; Loach told AFP at the festival. &#8220;There are whole sections of people who campaign for refugees.&#8221;</p>



<p>He said ‘The Old Oak’ was a necessary blast of positivity after more downbeat recent films, ‘I, Daniel Blake’ (which won the Palme in 2016) and ‘Sorry We Missed You’.</p>



<p>&#8220;Without hope there&#8217;s despair, and then you&#8217;re open to the far right and that destroys us,&#8221; Loach said.</p>



<p>&#8220;The working class is not defeated, we&#8217;re still in the game.&#8221;</p>



<p>Asked about still directing in his mid-80s, Loach joked: &#8220;If you get up and read the obituary columns and you&#8217;re not in them, it&#8217;s a good day. But I&#8217;ve been lucky to keep some health.&#8221;</p>



<p>Hard graft<br>His long-time writing partner Paul Laverty was full of praise for Loach&#8217;s dedication, saying the director still worked late for months on end to cast the film from local communities.</p>



<p>&#8220;That was like six months hard graft,&#8221; Laverty said, before having a friendly dig: &#8220;That&#8217;s fine when you&#8217;re 30 but when you&#8217;re 105…&#8221;</p>



<p>Laverty had far less kind things to say about Britain&#8217;s politicians, saying that Home Secretary Suella Braverman, known for her anti-migrant rhetoric, displayed &#8220;remarkable cruelty&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;She&#8217;s a scumbag who lives off the misery of other people,&#8221; said Laverty.</p>



<p>Solidarity used to mean &#8220;joining together and sharing,&#8221; Loach said.</p>



<p>&#8220;Today, it means charity… giving a small amount to the poor provided they are grateful and deserving and don&#8217;t cause a fuss and look like victims.&#8221;</p>



<p>Speaking about the deterioration of the National Health Service, Loach said &#8220;the extent of the crisis is catastrophic&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;We have the most sophisticated political class in the world controlling the image of Britain, but you look inside and it&#8217;s rotten to the core.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/ken-loach-at-cannes-working-class-is-undefeated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iraq unveils $17b transport project linking Europe and Mideast</title>
		<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/</link>
					<comments>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staff.ramdajs.com/?p=48</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iraq on Saturday presented an ambitious plan to turn itself into a regional transportation hub by developing its road and rail infrastructure, linking Europe with the Middle East. Once completed, the $17 billion project known as the &#8220;Route of Development&#8221; would span the length of the country, stretching 1,200 kilometres (745 miles) from the northern...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="1068" src="https://staff.ramdajs.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/prothomalo-english_2023-05_21286174-36b1-4fe9-8328-5b103471e0ba_838457_01_02.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-49"/></figure>



<p>Iraq on Saturday presented an ambitious plan to turn itself into a regional transportation hub by developing its road and rail infrastructure, linking Europe with the Middle East.</p>



<p>Once completed, the $17 billion project known as the &#8220;Route of Development&#8221; would span the length of the country, stretching 1,200 kilometres (745 miles) from the northern border with Turkey to the Gulf in the south.</p>



<p>Prime minister Mohamed Shia al-Sudani announced the project during a conference with transport ministry representatives from Iran, Jordan, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Syria, Turkey and the United Arab Emirates.</p>



<p>&#8220;We see this project as a pillar of a sustainable non-oil economy, a link that serves Iraq&#8217;s neighbours and the region, and a contribution to economic integration efforts,&#8221; Sudani said.</p>



<p>While further discussions are required, any country that wishes &#8220;will be able to carry out part of the project&#8221;, the Iraqi parliament&#8217;s transport committee said, adding the project could be completed in &#8220;three to five years&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;The Route of Development will boost interdependence between the countries of the region,&#8221; Turkey&#8217;s ambassador to Baghdad Ali Riza Guney said, without elaborating on what role his country would play in the project.</p>



<p>War-ravaged and beset by rampant corruption, oil-rich Iraq suffers from dilapidated infrastructure.</p>



<p>Its roads, riddled with potholes and poorly maintained, are in terrible condition.</p>



<p>Those connecting Baghdad to the north cross areas where sporadic attacks are still carried out by remnants of the Islamic State group.</p>



<p>Sudani has prioritised the reconstruction of the country&#8217;s road network, along with upgrading its failing electricity infrastructure.</p>



<p>Lack of &#8216;fluidity&#8217;<br>Developing the road and rail corridor would allow Iraq to capitalise on its geographical position, with the aim of making the country a transportation hub for goods and people moving between the Gulf, Turkey and Europe.</p>



<p>Work has already started to increase capacity at the commercial port of Al-Faw, on the shores of the Gulf, where cargo is to be unloaded before it embarks on the new road and rail links.</p>



<p>The project also includes the construction of around 15 train stations along the route, including in the major cities of Basra, Baghdad and Mosul, and up to the Turkish border.</p>



<p>The Gulf, largely bordered by Iran and Saudi Arabia, is a major shipping zone, especially for the transportation of hydrocarbons extracted by countries of the region.</p>



<p>Zyad al-Hashemi, an Iraqi consultant on international transport, cast doubt on the plan to develop the country into a transportation hub, saying it lacks &#8220;fluidity&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;Customers prefer to transport their goods directly from Asia to Europe, without going through a loading and unloading process,&#8221; that would see containers moved between ships and road or rail, he said.</p>



<p>Transport is a key sector in the global economy and Iraq&#8217;s announcement is the latest in other planned international mega-projects, including China&#8217;s &#8220;Belt and Road Initiative&#8221; announced in 2013 by its president Xi Jinping.</p>



<p>The planned works in that project would see 130 countries across Asia, Europe and Africa connected through land and sea infrastructure providing greater access to China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
