<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>International &#8211; G News Today</title>
	<atom:link href="https://staff.ramdajs.com/category/international/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:32:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Iraq unveils $17b transport project linking Europe and Mideast</title>
		<link>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/</link>
					<comments>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staff.ramdajs.com/?p=48</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iraq on Saturday presented an ambitious plan to turn itself into a regional transportation hub by developing its road and rail infrastructure, linking Europe with the Middle East. Once completed, the $17 billion project known as the &#8220;Route of Development&#8221; would span the length of the country, stretching 1,200 kilometres (745 miles) from the northern...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="1068" src="https://staff.ramdajs.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/prothomalo-english_2023-05_21286174-36b1-4fe9-8328-5b103471e0ba_838457_01_02.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-49"/></figure>



<p>Iraq on Saturday presented an ambitious plan to turn itself into a regional transportation hub by developing its road and rail infrastructure, linking Europe with the Middle East.</p>



<p>Once completed, the $17 billion project known as the &#8220;Route of Development&#8221; would span the length of the country, stretching 1,200 kilometres (745 miles) from the northern border with Turkey to the Gulf in the south.</p>



<p>Prime minister Mohamed Shia al-Sudani announced the project during a conference with transport ministry representatives from Iran, Jordan, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Syria, Turkey and the United Arab Emirates.</p>



<p>&#8220;We see this project as a pillar of a sustainable non-oil economy, a link that serves Iraq&#8217;s neighbours and the region, and a contribution to economic integration efforts,&#8221; Sudani said.</p>



<p>While further discussions are required, any country that wishes &#8220;will be able to carry out part of the project&#8221;, the Iraqi parliament&#8217;s transport committee said, adding the project could be completed in &#8220;three to five years&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;The Route of Development will boost interdependence between the countries of the region,&#8221; Turkey&#8217;s ambassador to Baghdad Ali Riza Guney said, without elaborating on what role his country would play in the project.</p>



<p>War-ravaged and beset by rampant corruption, oil-rich Iraq suffers from dilapidated infrastructure.</p>



<p>Its roads, riddled with potholes and poorly maintained, are in terrible condition.</p>



<p>Those connecting Baghdad to the north cross areas where sporadic attacks are still carried out by remnants of the Islamic State group.</p>



<p>Sudani has prioritised the reconstruction of the country&#8217;s road network, along with upgrading its failing electricity infrastructure.</p>



<p>Lack of &#8216;fluidity&#8217;<br>Developing the road and rail corridor would allow Iraq to capitalise on its geographical position, with the aim of making the country a transportation hub for goods and people moving between the Gulf, Turkey and Europe.</p>



<p>Work has already started to increase capacity at the commercial port of Al-Faw, on the shores of the Gulf, where cargo is to be unloaded before it embarks on the new road and rail links.</p>



<p>The project also includes the construction of around 15 train stations along the route, including in the major cities of Basra, Baghdad and Mosul, and up to the Turkish border.</p>



<p>The Gulf, largely bordered by Iran and Saudi Arabia, is a major shipping zone, especially for the transportation of hydrocarbons extracted by countries of the region.</p>



<p>Zyad al-Hashemi, an Iraqi consultant on international transport, cast doubt on the plan to develop the country into a transportation hub, saying it lacks &#8220;fluidity&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;Customers prefer to transport their goods directly from Asia to Europe, without going through a loading and unloading process,&#8221; that would see containers moved between ships and road or rail, he said.</p>



<p>Transport is a key sector in the global economy and Iraq&#8217;s announcement is the latest in other planned international mega-projects, including China&#8217;s &#8220;Belt and Road Initiative&#8221; announced in 2013 by its president Xi Jinping.</p>



<p>The planned works in that project would see 130 countries across Asia, Europe and Africa connected through land and sea infrastructure providing greater access to China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staff.ramdajs.com/2023/05/27/iraq-unveils-17b-transport-project-linking-europe-and-mideast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
